# 今天不會下雨 而且天很晴的哦
It's not gonna rain today. And it will a beautiful sunny day, you know.
# 很適合釣魚 兄弟 去挖點蚯蚓 等下我們去釣魚
It's a good day for fishing. Buddy! Go and dig some earthworms. Let's go fishing in a while.
# 好啊 可以
Sure! Good idea!
# 去那邊 那邊好多 我去 我去找一下那個魚竿
Over there. There are a lot. Let me, let me find the, I mean, the fishing rod.
# 你看 這裡有一個魚竿哦
Look! Here's fishing rod.
# 不知道是誰的
Who knows whose it is.
# 竟然想釣我家池塘裡面的魚
Somebody dares to catch the fish in my pond.
# 沒收了
It's confiscated.
# 剛好用這個
Perfect timing. I can,
# 這個魚竿去釣魚就行了
I can use it for our fishing today.
# 兄弟 有沒有挖到
Buddy! Any earthworms?
# 很多啊
A lot
# 很多
A lot?
# 對呀 過來過來過來
Yea! Come here, come here, come here.
# 抓幾個就夠了 不要那麼多
A couple of them is enough, not too many
# 哎呀 太多了
Aya! It's too many!
# 抓起來
Catch them!
# 等一下來嘛
A moment
# 夠了 夠了
Enough, enough
# 夠了
Enough
# 你看 桶又沒找到 找了一個鍋 這個鍋也可以裝魚的
Look! The bucket is no where to be found. Here's a pot. It can carry fish too.
# 去 去河邊釣
Let's go, to the riverside.
# 我們這邊很多魚釣的哦
There are of fish here at our place, you know.
# 河裡面的魚都是我放的 (註︰這個「都」字有「這些魚都是我的」的暗示，英文沒法表達出來，只有明示算了)
These are my fish. I put them into the river.
# 你看 上次我們抽水的時候看到有條大魚
Look! I saw a big fish when we were pluming out the water last time.
# 沒抓到 現在我拿魚鈎來 把它 看能不能把它勾起來
But we couldn't catch them. So I'm now coming with a hook. I'm gonna... Let's see if I can catch it.
# 看誰先釣到哦
Let's see who's gonna catch the first fish,
# 看誰先釣到
who's gonna catch the first fish.
# 這裡很多魚的哦 這裡
Here's a lot of fish, here.
# 咬啦 咬啦 快點 快點
It's biting, it's biting! C'mon, c'mon!
# 哪個 你的
Which one?
Yours
# 我的 已經在這裡來啦
Mine?
It's already here.
# 是不是
Are you sure?
# 等會 等會
A moment, a moment!
# 我把我的先拿走 不要 搞掉了
Let me take away mine first. I don't wanna, drop it.
# 哎呦 好像是咬了哦
Ayo! Seems that it's biting.
# 誒 是不是
Ey? Is it,
# 勾到草去了 勾到草上去了
getting hooked onto the grass, hooked onto the grass?
# 我看到它是從那邊過來
I saw it coming here from that side.
# 拉不過來
I can't pull it to me.
# 我來幫你弄
Let me give you a hand.
# 小心點哦
Be careful!
# 是魚 是魚 看到沒有 浮起來啦 看到沒有
It's a fish, really a fish! See? It's floating, see?
# 我沒看到
I can't see anything.
# 那不是嗎 浮起來了
Isn't that one a fish? It's floating.
# 拉綫啊 拉綫
Pull the line, pull it!
# 拉綫 扯不過來
Pull the line! It doesn't work.
# 來啦 來啦 來啦
It's coming, it's coming, it's coming!
# 誒呦 一條鯉魚
Eyo! It's a carp.
# 快點 別跑啦
Hurry up! Don't it be run away.
# 這裡這裡這裡 找到啦
Here, here, here. I got it.
# 你看 這條 小鯉魚
Look! It's a, small carp.
# 裝好水啦
I've filled the water.
# 別搞那麼多哦 等下抬不回去
Don't get too much water. You won't be able to take it back.
# 抬得回
Yes, I can.
# 哎呀 挺漂亮的
Aya! It's rather pretty.
# 回家啦回家啦 一條夠吃啦 不要那麼多
Let's go, let's go. One is enough for us. We don't need too many.
# 可以 你的技術比我的好
Not bad. You're more skilful than me.
# 收工 收工
Go, go, go!
# 這魚竿 收回去
This fishing rod. Let's take it back.
# 一人抬一個
Let's take one handle each.
# 這個刀老是
This knife is always,
# 很快就鈍掉了
it gets blunt very soon.
# 你看 兄弟 今天要吃你的
Look! Buddy, you'll be our meal today.
# 這是公的 這個魚
It's male, this fish.
# 哎呀 不好意思啊
Aya! I'm sorry.
# 我都還沒吃 你們想吃
Don't think of eating before me!
# 慢慢來 後面排隊
Not now, a moment. Line up behind me.
# 我要打點花
I'm gonna slice it a few times.
# 更入味哦 這樣就
It would be, more flavourful.
# 好啦 可以啦 不要割那麼多花
Alright! It's fine now. Not too many times.
# 割的差不多就行了
It's fine when it's enough.
# 這裡有一根筋的 這裡
Here's a tendon, here.
# 找不到 管它 就這樣吃
Can't find it. Never mind. Forget it!
# 好啦 我拿個盆子把它腌一下
Alright! I'm gonna get a pot and marinate it for a while.
# 腌一下就 下油鍋啦
Marinate it, and then, fry it.
# 誒呦 還想跑
Eyo! You still wanna run away?
# 加點鹽
Put some salt
# 鹽都結塊了
The salt is clumping.
# 好了 夠了
Alright. It's enough.
# 不下那麼多鹽
Not too much salt
# 加點料酒
Put some cooking wine
# 黑呦 沒啦
Heyo! No more?
# 加點油
Put some oil
# 加點油 讓它肌膚更滑
Put some oil, so that it has a smoother skin.
# 加點薑 去它的腥味
Put some ginger, to get rid of the fishy smell,
# 去它的腥味 加點醬油
get rid of the fishy smell. Put some soy sauce,
# 讓它更美味
so that it tastes even better.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 給你按一下摩
Give you a massage.
# 肚子上搞點生薑下去 (註︰他應該是說搞點生薑「給你」)
Put some ginger into your belly.
# 生薑生薑 從肚子裡面生出來的薑 (註︰這兩個騷話太難了，若有更好的翻譯，請建議)
Ginger, ginger, from the belly it was born and there it has its oriGIN,
# 叫生薑
that's why it's called GINger.
# 嘴巴上也塞一兩塊給你
Let me stuff some ginger into your mouth,
# 去下你的口臭
to get rid of your bad breath.
# 嗯 搓兩下
Um! Rub it over
# 好啦 腌個半個小時
Alright! Marinate it for half an hour,
# 直接
then,
# 下油鍋啦
fry it right away.
# 搞點油來 搞多一點
Put some oil, more oil
# 可以
Alright!
# 這條魚
This fish...
# 這個魚炸的 炸到它尾巴都斷啦
The fish, its tail has come off.
# 拿它尾巴
Let me take the tail.
# 肯定很香的哦
I'm sure that it's nice.
# 唉呦 好燙啊
Eyo! It's burning hot!
# 嗯~
Um~
# 很好吃哦
It's really tasty!
# 應該快熟啦
It should be done very soon.
# 把它撩起來
Let me scoop it up.
# 已經熟透啦
It's well done now.
# 好靚
Beautiful!
# 尾巴被我吃掉啦
I've already eaten the tail.
# 等一下 叫兄弟一起來吃
I'm gonna, ask my buddy to enjoy it with me.
# 你看 這個魚可以吧
Look! This fish is quite good, isn't it?
# 還不錯
Not bad
# 原生態的
It's natural and organic.
# 來來來
C'mon, c'mon, c'mon!
# 太燙啦
It's too hot!
# 小黑 來來來來
Blacky! C'mon, c'mon! Here, here!
# 趴到你身上去
She's gonna hop on you.
# 老是 老是弄我家的魚 手藝 手藝都變好了
You're, you're a much better cook now, after endless, endless practice using my fish.
# 拿你家的 魚來練手藝
I practise, using your, your fish.
# 下次 下次 你家 你
Next time, next time, your, your,
# 你家那個鵝可以拿來烤一下嘛
can we grill one of your geese?
# 可以
Sure!
# 好吃哦
Good, isn't it?
# 是好吃啊 特別香
Indeed.
It smells exceptionally good.
# 就是太燙了 你知道吧
It's just too hot, you know.
# 沒事
No worries
# 啊 太燙啦
Ah! It's too hot!
# 好啦 今天的視頻到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
# 還有個魚頭 給你
Here's still a fish head. It's yours.